Guide to the Paul P. Ewald papers, 1906-1990.
Ewald, Paul P. papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Paul P. Ewald papers, 1906-1990
4586
Peter Paul Ewald, 1888-
10.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, technical reports and reprints, drafts of articles, manuscripts, and subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, photographs, technical reports and reprints, drafts of articles, manuscripts, and subject files pertaining to Ewald's career as a scientist working in the field of x-ray crystallography; also, personal and family papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Scientist, crystallographer; professor, University of Munich, Queen's University at Belfast, and the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Professionally known as P. P. Ewald; personally known as Paul P. Ewald.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, photographs, technical reports and reprints, drafts of articles, manuscripts, and subject files pertaining to Ewald's career as a scientist working in the field of x-ray crystallography; also, personal and family papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ewald, Peter Paul, 1888-
Subjects:
X-ray crystallography--Study and teaching.; Crystallography--Study and teaching.; Scientists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- The Crystallography of Human Stones - Acknowledgements, Chs. 1-2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Crystallography of Human Stones - Chs. 3-6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Crystallography of Human Stones - Chs. 7-8, Bibliography, etc. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Borrmann, Gerhard from Dr. G. Hildebrandt, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Poststift, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Crystallography of Human Stones - Figures (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Crystallography of Human Stones - Plates I-V (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Crystallography of Human Stones - Lonsdale and Sutor, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Hsum Hu, S. R. Goodman - Pole Figures of Cu, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bragg Obituary for Physics Today mss., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Recollections of Braggs, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Figures for Rev. Mod. Phys., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Korrespondenz R. A. Lueb, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Pension [Pensionierung?], 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Removal to Brooklyn, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Brooklyn, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Reise nach Brooklyn, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Korrespondenz - Laue Feier, Berlin 2-3-79, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Beyerchen, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Oklahoma Talk, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Menzer, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Glocker, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Groth mss., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Festschrift Y. Cauchois - "Correction" of Bragg Law, 1-29-79, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Aminoff Medal - Stockholm-Stuttgart-Grenoble, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Laue Feier, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- Reprints - Bristol Paper, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- Reprint - Poststift, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Paper: The Solid State, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Reprints (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Marina Ewald, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
- K. Herrmann, C. Herman, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- 50 Years - National Schools Questionnaire, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- re Ewald Festschrift - proofs, correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- re Ewald Festschrift - Heno, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- II Heno-Ewald, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Ewald-Heno Heno-Ewald corrected revisions (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Heno-Ewald - original 3 ray ms., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Australian Notes, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Munksgaard - Heno-Ewald, Ewald-Heno, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Intern - Nickel Co. Scholarships, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- IBM, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Correspondence re Melbourne and Australia, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Correspondence for Paris, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- E. E. Symposia - P.I.B.-MRI - Solid State, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Dumont Gutachter, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Correspondence - Eitel and Verlagsgesellschaft, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Purdue Lectures, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Hans Bethe - Seattle Summer - Lecture and Seminar Notes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Overlap in Diamond; Electrical Properties of Thin Metallic Films; Potentials of Crystals and Half Crystals, 1936, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Juretschke - Application of Group Theory and Physical Properties of Crystala, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Symposium - P.I.B.: Electroluminescence and Photoconduction, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Symposium, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Surface Energy Calculations, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Surface Energy, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58-59)
- Surface Energy Reprints (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Stuttgart, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Hydro-Electrodyn Optics, Belfast - Hydrodynamics Courses II and III, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Hydro-Electrodyn Optics, Belfast - III, 1st Term: Electromagnetic Theory, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Hydro-Electrodyn Optics, Belfast - V, Optics; Future Development of the Department of Math. Physics, Queensland U., 1948-1949, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Guggenheim - R. S. "Obituary" of P. P. E.French Life Dates, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Electron Theory of Matter 8380, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Electron Theory of Metter 8380, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Theory of Electrons, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sale of Journals, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Article: Carl Hermann for Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- From Kyoto - IV Cryst Assembly, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence - Wagenfeld, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence - Hosemann, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence - Wolfson, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence Donnay, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence - H. Klapper, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Cambridge Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
- Cambridge Correspondence - Niggli, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Honl, Helmut, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Two samples of Acta. Cryst. correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Megaw - Chayes, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Beatrice May, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Bea May, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- J. D. H. Donnay translation of 1921 paper by Ewald, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Rontgen, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Rontgen, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Borrmann, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Borrmann Effect, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Borrmann, Gerhard, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Borrmann-Campbell Effect (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Borrmann, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Fourier Symmetry, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Notes on Slater,....for Coloquia on Irregular Crystal, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Missouri Talk, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- ACA Marquette Meeting, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Symposia, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Projects, Biography, etc. - Archives copy (Box 2, Folder 37)
- APS talk - Early Xray Diffraction, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- de Santallana, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Russia, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Symposuim on Biogenesis, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Madrid, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Bristol meeting, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Bowden and Co., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Half-crystal, Optical and Static, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- [see note inside folder], 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Solid State Circuits, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Metal Texture, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- History of Science Correspondence: Beyerchen, Olby, Weiner, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 49-50)
- New Historical Proposal - pages 1, 4, 5, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Verkauf Holzhausen, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Colloquium - Troy, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Address at Ann Arbor (june 24), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Small Calculations- Notes, Diffraction reprints, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Complex Space Groups, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Harvard talk - main copy, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Leybold, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Leybold, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Center for History of Recent Physics - Niels Bohr Library, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- The Royal Society, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- History of Quantum Physics including Born interview by Ewald, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- History of Quantum Physics interviews, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Sources for History of Quantum Physics, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Sources for History of Quantum Physics - T. S. Juhn Archives, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 65-66)
- McGill/Laval, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Meetings - Summer School - Limoges, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Meetings - IV Cryst., Amsterdam, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Meetings - IV Cryst., Amsterdam, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 70-71)
- ACA Charlottesville, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Purdue - meetings, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Rensselaer - meetings, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Donnay (Sutor), 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Donnay, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Donnay's John Teeler Effect, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Rupert Brooke, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Munchner Kolloquium, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Summer Travel, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- April talks: Washington; Queens; Cornell, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Summer Visitors, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Sommerfeld, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
- Strukturbericht Correspondence - Johnson Reprints, ACA, Oosthock, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Jose Donnay's Retirement, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Airborne Instruments Consultations, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- UNESCO teaching Cryst. 4 Project, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- L. V. Azaroff on X-Ray Physics, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- RCA X-ray School, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Correspondence - IV Cryst, M. P. Gesellschaft, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
- Parma Summer Institute - preparatory correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Talks: Parma Institute; IBM talk - "60 Years of Crystal Optics", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- S. Ogawa, D. Watanabe, 1956-58 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Microwave Research Institute (MRI), 1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- WoolfsonTaylor (Manchester), 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Acta Cryst. (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
- Method Summer Acta Cryst., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Acta Cryst. (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
- Ralph W. G. Wyckoff, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Satio Takagi (Box 3, Folder 32)
- H. Witte (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Acta Cryst. - Atomic Factors (Box 3, Folder 34)
- W. Parrish, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Ogawa, Fujiwara, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Gunther Kunze, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- D. McLachlan, Jr. F584, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Kathleen Lonsdale photos (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Comments on Inverse Pole Figure Methods, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- J. Kakinoki and Y. Komura, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Salloch, Henry E. Adv. Service, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Shipment of books from Belfast, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Schwarz, Dr. G., 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Society of the Sigma XI, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Solid State Physics - Div. of Amer. Physical Soc., 1050-55 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Committee on Solids, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Sommerfeld's OPTIK, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- R, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- ACA - Gordon Conference, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Visit at Tamiment, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Business and Committee Meetings - Tamiment, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- ACA - Tamiment Meeting - Registrations, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 53-54)
- ACA Meeting - Tamiment, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- U. S. National Committee for Crystallography - Tamiment, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- ACA News, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- ACA Pittsburgh, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- ACA Pasadena, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- ACA Meeting at Poly, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- ACA Meeting - Cambridge, Mass., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- ACA Ann Arbor, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- ACA Publications Committee, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- ACA News, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- ACA - Physics Today, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- ACA - Pickett, H. W., 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- ACA - Rutgers University, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- ACA - Yudowitch, K. L. (Biblio), 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- ACA Miscellaneous Info (by-laws, elections, etc.), 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Sommerfeld - mss., 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Sommerfeld mss. - foreword, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Sommerfeld, A. (personal), 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Staudinger, Mrs. E., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- S, 1951-1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Tavora, E., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Tommasi, Dr. G. B. de Vignano, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- T, 1950-1956 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- University of Utah, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- USA National Committee for Chrystallography (USANCCr), 1947-1956 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- USA National Committee of Physics, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- U, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Valence Theory, New Aspects of, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Verma, Dr. A. E., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Visitors from England, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Volterra, E., 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- V, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- W, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Weill, Mme. A. R., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- West Point, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Yale meeting - department heads, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- X, Y, Z, 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- ACA Applications for Membership, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- ACA - Bond Printing and Publishing Service, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- ACA - Bulletin Analytique, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- ACA - Correspondence (misc.), 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- ACA - Correspondence (misc.)II, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
- ACA - Council, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- ACA - Evans, Dr. Howard T. J., 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- ACA - Florida State University, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- ACA - The Letter Shop, Inc., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- ACA - Membership (dues, reminder for payment, etc.), 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- ACA meeting - Chicago, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 44-46)
- ACA meeting - Washington, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- ACA meeting - New Hampton, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 48-49)
- ACA meeting - Penn State College, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- USANCCr meeting - Washington, DC - minutes, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Name lists, committees, etc., 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Diamond Club - Cambridge, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- American Physics Society; NYSSAPS Fall Meeting, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- ACA meeting - Cambridge, Mass., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- ACA meeting - Ann Arbor, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- ACA Tamiment meeting, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- ACA meeting - Chicago, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- ACA meeting - Washington, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- ACA meeting - New hampshire, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- ACa meeting - Penn State, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- ASXRED-Phla. meeting (ACA), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- P208-Dornberger, et al, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- L145-2080 Jillinek, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Chandrasekaran, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- F79 Yu Article, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 66-67)
- F105 Geller and Hoard, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- E58-E136, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- F467 and F468 Goldsmith, Laves, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- F486 Hauptman, Karle, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- E187-E242, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- E184-336 Watanabe, Saito, Koyama, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- E138-E198, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- P177 Westphal (Raether), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- E642-E903, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- P190 Vand and Pepinsky, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- P191 Ludeman, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- P196 Vand and Pepinsky, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- P187 Jahrreiss, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 80)
- P184 Niehrs, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 81)
- P183 Hoffrogge and Weyerer, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 82)
- P178 Ludemann and Raether, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 83)
- P176 Brogan, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- P175 Wunderlich and Mellor, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- P173 Graf, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- P172 Aebi, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- P170 Jagodzinski, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- P168, P169 Grenville-Wells, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Niggli, Paul, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- P164 Winkler, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- P163 Schlenk, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- P162 Lenne, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- P161 Pon, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- P154 Winkler, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- N5, N6 Kambe and Miyake, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- N3, N4 Uyeda, Tchinokawa, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- N2 Kainuma, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Takagi and Suzuki, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- N11 Miyake and Uyeda, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- F85-F121, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- F-mss. between F114 and F157, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- P152 Mitra, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- P151 Bader, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- P150 Perdok (Jakob), 1952 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- P14 Watanabe, Ueda, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- P148 Hosemann, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- P146 and P147 Dasgupta and Maitra, Basak and Dasgupta, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- P145 Atoji, Oda, Watanabe, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- P144 Hoseman, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- P142 Kakudo and Watase, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- P141 Nowacki, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- P140 Allentoff and Wright (Box 5, Folder 30)
- P138 Krishnan and Roy, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- P137 Wood and Townsley, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- P135 Fumi, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- P134 Atoji-Watanabe, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- P133 Frohnmeyer and Glocker, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- P131 Nowacki, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- P129 Tommasi, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- P128 Hosemann and Bagehi[?], 1952 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Buerger Review, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- P127 Schubert, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- P126 Evans - [?], 1952 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- W62a,b Bertaut, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- W14 - W61, 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- W18,19 W20 Luzzati (Box 5, Folder 44)
- W7 - W10, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- P117 Brue and Perez, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- P201 Marsal, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- P122 Renninger, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Keller, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- P233 Liebau, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- P248 Lilabati Ray, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- E1029 - 1732 S. Chandzasekhaz - A Simple Model for Optical Activity [empty]; "Refused - back to Evans[?], 1 Dec. 1955", 1955 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- P246 James and Straumanes, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- F578 Eichhorn - On the Use of Gen. Inclinations, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- F573 Merritt, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- F552 Templeton, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- F461/462 Magdoff and Crick, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- F433 Alexopoulos, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 58)
- F449 Waser, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 59)
- F439 KatzF451 HirshfeldF470 Turner, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- F431 Rollett and Davis, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 61)
- F472 Jensen, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 62)
- F436 Weiss et al, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 63)
- P238 Niggli, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 64)
- P202 Vand and Pepinsky, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- E785-1308 Hoerni and Wooster, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 66)
- F454 Eichhorn, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 67)
- W65 Bertant, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 68)
- P511 Fisher, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 69)
- F500 Hauptman-Karle, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 70)
- P230 Knowles, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 71)
- F494 Harker, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Short Papers editorially, 1952-1958 (Box 5, Folder 73-75)
- Book Reviews for Acta, 1951-1958 (Box 5, Folder 76)
- E485-822 Miyake, Kohra, Takagi, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 77)
- E475-803 Quarashi and Vand; P132 Quarashi, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 78)
- P99 Bujor, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 79)
- P116-117, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 80)
- P115 Venkatarayudu and Krishnamurty, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 81)
- P113 Deas, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 82)
- P93, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 83)
- E493-835, E494-834 Kakinoki and Komura, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 84)
- F353-440, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 85)
- F150-F178, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 86)
- P73-P85, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 87)
- P79 Miyake, Kohra, Uyeda, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 88)
- P80-P88, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 89)
- P96-P97, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 90)
- P114 Tunell-Pauling, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 91)
- Hosemann, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 92)
- P110-P112, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 93)
- P106, P108, P104, P102, P101, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 94)
- P100 Zapffe, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 95)
- P338-P339 Karle and Hauptman, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 96)
- P334 Kiebau; P335 Hilmen, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 97)
- F483 Magdoff, Crick, Luzzati, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 98)
- P323 Wolff and Broder, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 99)
- P324 Zocher and Machado, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 100)
- P330 Meyerhoff and Ungelenck, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 101)
- N. Kato, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 102)
- W110-W114 (Box 5, Folder 103)
- P359 Jaswon, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 104)
- F830 Ferguson and Co., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 105)
- P360/361 Ramachandran and Raman, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 106)
- Hahn, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 107)
- W105-107 Bertaut, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 108)
- P337 Motzkus, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 109)
- P354 Weiss, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 110)
- P340 Meyerhoff, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 111)
- P348 Wagner, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 112)
- P314 Alexopoulos, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 113)
- P298 Gillis, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 114)
- Acta, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 115)
- P325 Pike, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 116)
- P323 Wolff-Broder, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 117)
- P313 Mayer-Hiedemann, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 118)
- Barnes, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 119)
- P311 Katz, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 120)
- Kurze, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 121)
- P309 Chatterjee, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 122)
- F737 Birman, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 123)
- P307 Posner, Perloff, Diozco, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 124)
- P305 Vand, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 125)
- F733 Karle, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 126)
- P296 Hussuhl, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 127)
- P295 Wolfsteig, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 128)
- P294 Schade, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 129)
- P297 Hanic, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 130)
- P287 Houska-Averbach, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 131)
- P279 Geller-Pauling, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 132)
- Karle and Hauptman, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 133)
- Liebau, Kindemann, Nozdmeyer, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 134)
- F707 Hauptman-Karle, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 135)
- H32 Pauling, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 136)
- W91 Housty and Clastre, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 137)
- P280 N. Norman, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 138)
- Mackay, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 139)
- P282 J. Waser, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 140)
- W96 Bertaut, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 141)
- P291 Bode, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 142)
- P285 Curti, Riganti, Locchi, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 143)
- Straumanis, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 144)
- P278 Jeffrey, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 145)
- P277 J. Zemann, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 146)
- W92 Luzzati, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 147)
- W93-W95 Wunderlich, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 148)
- P269 Dornberger-Schiff, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 149)
- P271 Boettcher and Thun, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 150)
- P268 Gerald, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 151)
- Kratky Review, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 152)
- Laval, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 153)
- F591 Geller, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 154)
- P257 Kunze, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 155)
- F590 Trueblood and Mayer, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 156)
- P254 Liebau, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 157)
- P249 Mookherji, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 158)
- P262 Halla, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 159)
- P250/251 Baur, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 160)
- P261 Holser, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 161)
- P260 G. Teufer, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 162)
- F586 Ibers, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 163)
- F487 Tudker, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 164)
- P256 Bertinotti, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 165)
- P252 Alexander and Pitman, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 166)
- E990-1659 Shaw, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 167)
- F557 Karle, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- F565 Herbstein, Borie, Averbach, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- F428 Lieberman-Zirinsky, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- P239 Richter-Brietling, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- P253 Martin, W. G., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- F523/524 Lang, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- H47 Schomaker, et al, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- P323 Ewald, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- P355 V. Marmo, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- P345 Hoppe, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- P349 Parrish Report, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Acta Cryst. reprints (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
- Dahlem Talk, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Seminaraufgaben - Stuttgart, 1923-1936 (Box 6, Folder 15)